<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Counties within the MESB Jurisdiction</origin><title>Road Centerlines (Geospatial Advisory Council Schema)</title><pubinfo><publish>Metropolitan Council</publish></pubinfo><pubdate>20200303</pubdate><onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/us-mn-state-metrogis-trans-road-centerlines-gac</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This dataset was created by a joint collaborative project involving the technical and managerial GIS staff from the ten Metropolitan Counties (Anoka, Carver, Chisago, Dakota, Hennepin, Isanti, Ramsey, Scott, Sherburne and Washington), the Metropolitan Emergency Services Board, MetroGIS and the Metropolitan Council. Core needs this dataset are intended to satisfy include:

- Vehicular routing;
- Address geocoding;
- Next Generation 911 call routing and location validation;
- Emergency services dispatching;
- Linear referencing uses;
- Cartographic representation of road features;

For specific questions regarding centerline alignments or attributes, please contact the county below
Anoka: https://www.anokacounty.us/315/GIS
Carver: gis@co.carver.mn.us
Chisago: gisservices@chisagocountymn.gov
Dakota: gis@co.dakota.mn.us
Hennepin: gis.info@hennepin.us
Isanti: Nate.Kirkwold@co.isanti.mn.us
Ramsey: RCGISMetaData@co.ramsey.mn.us
Sherburne: gis@co.sherburne.mn.us
Scott: gis@co.scott.mn.us
Washington: gis@co.washington.mn.us</abstract><purpose>The goal of this dataset is to facilitate the creation and sustained maintenance of a local/regional road
centerline dataset that can be used to meet the needs of local and regional partner agencies.

Note:  The Geospatial Commons file geodatabase download contains a version with domains (trans_road_centerline_gac.gdb) and a version with domains removed (trans_road_centerlines_gac_NoDomain.gdb).</purpose><supplinf>Twin Cities Metro Area</supplinf></descript><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>Continually</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-94.012</westbc><eastbc>-92.732</eastbc><northbc>45.415</northbc><southbc>44.471</southbc></bounding></spdom><accconst>None. This dataset is public domain under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13). If the dataset is not available from the Online Linkage in Section 6, please contact the Distribution Contact Person.</accconst><useconst>None. This dataset is public domain under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).</useconst><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>Continually</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo><current>Counties submit data to this aggregated dataset at their determined interval.  The MetroGIS aggregation process runs nightly and accepts the most current version available to the aggregate (see note below).</current></timeperd><keywords><place><placekey>Minnesota, Twin Cities Metro, Anoka, Carver, Chisago, Dakota, Hennepin, Isanti, Ramsey, Scott, Sherburne, Washington</placekey></place><theme><themekey>centerlines, streets, routing, geocoding, 911 , emergency services, dispatching, linear referencing, free, open</themekey></theme></keywords><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>MetroGIS</cntorg><cntper>GIS Contact</cntper></cntperp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal></cntaddr><cntemail>metrogis-contacts@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><distinfo><distliab>NOTICE:  The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).  THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes.  The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate.  You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data.  You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features.  If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, it is recommended that the GIS Data include a copy of this disclaimer and this metadata.</distliab><stdorder><ordering>See Online Linkage Below</ordering></stdorder><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council</cntorg><cntper>Jon Hoekenga</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>GIS System Administrator</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651.602.1561</cntvoice><cntemail>jonathan.hoekenga@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20200303</metd><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>MetroGIS</cntorg><cntper>GIS Contact</cntper></cntperp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal></cntaddr><cntemail>metrogis-contacts@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><eainfo><overview><eaover>Attribute definitions can be found within Road Centerline Data Standard documentation  
https://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/roadcenterline/index.html
</eaover></overview></eainfo><dataqual><lineage><procstep><procdesc>This dataset has been updated from the MRCC standard to the Minnesota Geospatial Advisory Council (GAC) Road Centerline Data Standard which was based of the MRCC schema</procdesc></procstep></lineage><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>This varies between counties</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>NA</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc></dataqual><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref></metadata>